<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Sciences | lacaudillomata</title>
    <link>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/tag/computational-sciences/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lacaudillomata.github.io/tag/computational-sciences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computational Sciences</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/media/icon_hu744bacd88a4336fd6cdb18452799d0a4_39022_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Computational Sciences</title>
      <link>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/tag/computational-sciences/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale Methods For Geophysical Electromagnetics Modeling</title>
      <link>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/project/2017-multiscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/project/2017-multiscale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The focus of this investigation is to study how to reduce the computational cost
of simulating the behavior of electromagnetic fields in complicated geophysical
settings. This type of simulations are crucial to the exploration of buried natural
resources (mineral, groundwater and hydrocarbon deposits) using electromagnetic methods. However, the size of the computation they involve often exceeds
the limits of average computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This investigation proposes innovative mathematical alternatives — multiscale finite elements and finite volume methods — that achieve a great reduction of the problem’s size and the simulation cost without sacrificing much accuracy. It also opens the door to use such alternatives to create more powerful computational engines capable of simulating electromagnetic fields in larger and more complex geophysical settings than currently
is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was done as part of my doctoral dissertation. To provide more context, this study was the first one in the literature to demonstrate the practical use of the proposed alternatives in the context of geophysical
electromagnetic problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upscaling Methods For Geophysical Electromagnetics Modeling</title>
      <link>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/project/2017-upscaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/project/2017-upscaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The focus of this investigation is to study how to reduce the computational cost
of simulating the behavior of electromagnetic fields in complicated geophysical
settings. This type of simulations are crucial to the exploration of buried natural
resources (mineral, groundwater and hydrocarbon deposits) using electromagnetic methods. However, the size of the computation they involve often exceeds
the limits of average computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This investigation proposes innovative mathematical alternatives — upscaling finite elements and finite volume methods — that achieve a great reduction of the problem’s size and the simulation cost without sacrificing much accuracy. It also opens the door to use such alternatives to create more powerful computational engines capable of simulating electromagnetic fields in larger and more complex geophysical settings than currently
is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was done as part of my doctoral dissertation. To provide more context, this study was the first one in the literature to demonstrate the practical use of the proposed alternatives in the context of geophysical
electromagnetic problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5ta Fachada: A System For Automating and Optimizing Steel Roof Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/project/2011-quinta-fachada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lacaudillomata.github.io/project/2011-quinta-fachada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;El proyecto consiste en desarrollar un laboratorio virtual (software) que realiza el
análisis, el cálculo y la optimización de estructuras de acero rolado en frío, así como la cuantificación de los materiales utilizados en la construcción de la techumbre completa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El software está dotado con una interfase de usuario fácil de usar, intuitiva
y amigable. El análisis estructural considera cargas de peso propio, muertas y vivas a las que estará sometida la estructura en condiciones de servicio, además se consideran los efectos de viento y sismo para la República Mexicana de acuerdo a la normatividad vigente de la Comisión Federal de Electricidad (CFE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El optimizadorestá basado en métodos de minimización de entropía con restricciones múltiples
evaluando cada una de las estructuras por el método de la rigidez, el cual genera matrices ralas. El sistema de ecuaciones resultante se puede resolver con una variedad
de métodos directos e iterativos, al respecto de estos últimos, se han implementado
algoritmos de última generación dentro del software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cabe mencionar que para la evaluación de la eficiencia de la estructura
se utiliza la normativa vigente para diseño de elementos de acero rolado en frío
para la República Mexicana AISI-ASD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La combinación adecuada del seguimiento de las normatividades vigentes, la implementación del optimizador y los métodos matriciales para el cálculo de estructuras, aunado al ambiente grafico fácil de usar y amigable para el usuario final, han resultado en un potente software que
genera soluciones de vivienda económicas, confiables, seguras y estéticas, favoreciendo
así a un amplio sector de la sociedad mexicana.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
